Guide to the Winterhouse Art and Design Collection of Ephemera
Yale University Arts Library
Winterhouse Art and Design collection of ephemera
1957-2010
ART 23
Yale University Arts Library
0.42
(1 box)
The collection contains a variety of design-related printed ephemera collected by William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand in the course of their work as principals of Winterhouse Design and later Winterhouse Institute.
Drenttel, William, 1953-2013
Helfand, Jessica, 1960-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand, 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Winterhouse was a design consultancy founded by partners William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand. According to their website, "Winterhouse Studio focuse[d] on editorial development and online media; cultural and educational institutions; and social innovation initiatives... Winterhouse Institute focuse[d] on non-profit, self-initiated projects that support design education as well as social and political initiatives."
Scope and Contents
The collection contains a variety of design-related printed ephemera collected by William Drenttel and Jessica Helfand in the course of their work as principals of Winterhouse Design and later Winterhouse Institute.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically by year of publication.
Design; Printed ephemera
- Box listing, 1957-2010
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Nash, Ogden. The boy who laughed at Santa Claus. [Canada]: Cooper & Beatty, 1957., 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - W. A. Dwiggins: 1880-1956., [1957]; 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gedanken und problem beim Entwurf von Werkschriften / Hermann Zapf. Frankfurt am Main: D. Stempel AG, 1958., 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - George Salter: a third of a century of graphic work. New York: Gallery 303., 1961; 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Four letters from William Morris is published on the 150th anniversary of his birth March 24, 1984. San Francisco: Arion Press., 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Frutiger, Adrian. Der Prophet Jona. Köniz: Könizer Galerie., 1988; 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Officina Bodoni & the Stamperia Valdonega: an exhibition marking the 100th anniversary of the birth of Giovanni Mardersteig. New York: Grolier Club., 1992; 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Manuzio, Aldo. Two letters concerning Aldus Manutius, printer of Venice. New York: Kelly-Winterton Press., 1992; 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Frank Stella broadsides: architecture and art., [1997]; 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [Who if not us?]., [1997]; 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Swiss poster: art of ten masters, 1953-2002, posters from the collection of Tom Strong / text by Bez Ocko and Jean Benoit-Levy., 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - David Byrne: March 6 – April 26, 2003. New York City: Pace/MacGill Gallery., 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav. Controlled visual flow. New York: Marquardt & Co., 2003 (Design and paper, number 13)., 1 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Sutnar, Ladislav. Shape, line, and color. New York: Marquardt & Co., 2003. (Design and paper, number 19)., 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Whirled. Chesapeake, VA, 2004. Final edition., 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Zeitgeist et typographie. S.l: Trio communication-marketing., 2004; 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 50 Russian children's books, 1881-1939: a selection of books from the collection of Sasha Lurye., 2006; 1 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - AIGA 50 Books / 50 Covers of 2005., 2006; 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Craig Frazier Collection 2: for licensing. Mill Valley, CA: Craig Frazier Studio., 2006; 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A Toast to Crouwel. Miami Beach., 2008; 1 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The undiscovered letter. New York: Moleskine, ADC Publications., 2008; 1 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Unit:Design/Research. Space and structure. London: Unit Editions., 2010; 1 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Interventions: six collaborative projects between social science and design., undated; 1 (Box 1, Folder 23)